and no and then there's the huge mistake
y no y después está el error garrafal
that he makes that like I'm telling you the
que él comete que como yo yo te digo la
truth I saw it watching it a while ago on
verdad lo veía viendo hace tiempo en
Instagram then one day I see that the
instagram entonces un día veo que el
headboard of the bed eh it was It was
respaldar de la cama aj eh era Era
always the same video and then I
siempre lo mismo video y entonces yo le
sent him a friend I said dude this
mando un amigo le digo boludo este
headboard on the bed and I started looking for
respald en la cama y me puse a buscar
hotels and I had already known the case
hoteles y yo ya había conocido el caso
of one who had gone because of the regime and
de uno que había ido por el régimen y
had stayed at the Melia and I made
había quedado en el en el Melia y hice
the comparison he's running out of that
la comparación está quedándose sin ese
hotel but you could see a little piece of the
hotel pero se veía un pedacito al
headboard and I didn't say anything you know why I said
respald y no dije nada viste porque dije
Well I'm done for p
Bueno me he cho para p pasaron pasaron
the videos went by the videos went by a month went by and he was leaving all
los videos pasó un mes y él se iba
emboldened and showing more parts of the
envalentonado y mostrando más partes del
hotel until he was directly
Hotel hasta que ya directamente era
shameless and F for the hallway and everything
desvergonzado y F para el pasillo y todo
Yes he didn't care about anything And of course let's see
Sí si no le importaba nada Y claro a ver
explaining to a person who is
explicarle a a a una persona que es
alien to politics why socialism
ajena a la política porque el socialismo
is bad because of liberalism well or the
es malo por el liberalismo bueno o lo
rest takes a lot of time now
demás requiere un montón de tiempo ahora
socialism as a tool has
el socialismo como herramienta ha
used the rich are bad it does that
utilizado el los ricos son malos eso lo
all the time it does it in Spain
hace todo el tiempo lo hac en España
all the time  the rich are sons of
todo el tiempo el rico es un hijo de
[ __ ] money in the wrong hands
[__] el dinero en las manos incorrectas
for example if you have money you're
por ejemplo si vos tenés dinero vos sos
a son of a [ __ ] now yes yes Pedro
un hijo de [__] ahora si si Pedro
Sanchez has money and well he was a
Sánchez tiene dinero y bueno él fue un
successful politician or whatever you see
exitoso político o lo que sea viste
money makes a son of a [ __ ] the people
dinero hace hijo de [__] las personas
we hate but even so it is frowned upon to
que odiamos pero aún así está mal visto
have money and that happens in all
tener dinero y eso pasa en todos los
socialist countries Argentina for example
países socialistas Argentina por ejemplo
people who have money do not dare to
la gente que tiene dinero no se anima a
buy the car that they would like to be able to
comprar el auto que quisiera que pudiese
buy they buy there sometimes a H less so as
comprar compra por ahí a veces un H meno
not to raise too much alarm or you do not
para no levantar demasiada alarma o no
walk around with your iPhone in the street you see you do not
andas con el iPhone en la calle viste no
give yourself away well Aha what did
te regalas bueno Ajá qué es lo que hizo
Michelo do Michelo he showed himself to be a millionaire in
michelo michelo se mostró millonario en
a poor country in a country that has a
un país pobre en un país que tiene una
logic of the antim millionaire there where he makes
lógica del antim millonario ahí donde se
mistakes and those kinds of blows the
equivoca y esa clase de golpes el
regime does not forgive you so that
régimen no te las Perdona entonces eso
must have brought him problems with the
le debe haber traído problemas con el
regime itself
propio régimen
m that for me really really screwed him
m eso para mí posta posta que Lo jodió
internally and begins to patch up a
internamente y empieza a empar una
situation that had already started he
situación que ya había empezado él ya
was already having the downgrade that they
estaba teniendo el downgrade que lo
were lowering his category but on top of that he
estaban bajando de categoría pero encima
sent that because I tell you by date date
se mandó eso porque te digo por fecha
pun I start making videos
fecha pun yo empieza a sacar videos una
once he's no longer at the five
vez que él no está más en el hotel cinco
star hotel Yeah, I mean, in
estrellas Sí o sea a él lo increpa de
fact, women yell at him on the street for that kind
hecho la mujer por la calle por ese tipo
of thing, like because he's attracting
de cuestiones o sea porque va llamando
attention, he's not a person who goes
la atención no es una persona que pase
unnoticed, of course,
desapercibido claro y no
but what do I know? Let's see, I earn very well and I
pero yo que sé a ver yo gano muy bien y
could pay for a much better place than the one I
podría pagarme un lugar mucho mejor del
'm living in. But I'm
que estoy viviendo Pero yo estoy
living in a house where literally
viviendo en una casa donde donde literal
the other day a plant passed from the
el otro día me un una planta pasó del
patio into the roof and started growing
patio entró al techo y empezó a crecer
inside my
adentro de mi
house. Well, that's because you get attached
casa Bueno pero eso ya porque uno le
to places, right? It's not
coge cariño a los sitios no eh No está
full of humidity, but yes, I do
lleno de humedad esto pero sí sí yo le
have affection for it, but my point is that there are
tengo cariño pero mi mi punto es que hay
realities, I mean, easier an
realidades digo más fácil un lavaplato
automatic dishwasher in Argentina means having
automático Argentina significa tener
money, the automatic dishwasher is not normal,
dinero elato automático no es normal
okay, of course, the T norm goes with security,
vale claro el T norm va con seguridad
he says they are his friends. But
que él dice que son sus amigos Pero
well, in that way, of course, there are things
bueno de aquella forma claro Hay cosas
that in certain countries mean having
que en ciertos países significa tener
money and Michel showed it too many,
dinero y Michel lo mostró demasiadas
okay, but I mean, he
vale pero o sea
really deserves it because we don't know
realmente se lo merece porque no sabemos
yet, maybe one day we will have a
todavía a lo mejor algún día tenemos una
way to quantify it, no, or or or, they're
forma de cuantificarlo no o o o Iran
coming out, case in point, but really, what the [ __ ] is that,
saliendo caso pero realmente que se jod
man, but  how many people are not involved
tío pero cuánta gente que no est metida
in social media or whatever and have seen a Tito
en redes o que tal y haya visto un Tito
by Michelo and have said Hey, I'm going to go to
de michelo y ha dicho Oye voy a irme
Venezuela, not to How many people have you
para para Venezuela no a Cuánta gente ha
put in danger with your advertising What is what
puesto en peligro con su publicidad Cuál
is the
es cuál es el
endgame, what do I know honestly
endgame yo que sé honestamente
Look, this happens with all dictatorships,
Mira esto pasa con todas las dictaduras
I think it is born from the dictator's death. It
yo creo que nace de la pararia del
is easier to have a buffoon who
dictador es más fácil tener un bufón que
says there is no poverty than to solve
dice que no hay pobreza que solucionar
poverty. You
la pobreza
see, he propagates you say that it is going downhill,
viste propaga tú dices que va para abajo
but I do not rule out that they will put on a
pero yo no descarto que le pongan un una
revolt there, a program? Ah, you
revuelta allí un programa Ah que vos
say that they will bring him back, yes, it could be
decís que que lo vuelvan sí puede ser
that they will put on a little television program for him,
que le pongan un programita de
but Queen, but
televisión pero Queen pero Pero puede
Queen could be a lot of responsibilities
ser Queen un montón de responsabilidades
That does not mean that they are going to put him on
Eso no significa que lo vayan a meter en
the table where the loot is distributed, it is
la mesa donde se reparte el botín está
clear. Apart from that, we agree
claro No aparte Estamos de acuerdo en
that when Maduro sees Michelo, he thinks
que maduro cuando ve a michelo piensa
that he is objectively an
que es objetivamente un
[ __ ], that is a difficult question,
[__] esa es una pregunta difícil
man, I do not think he considers him his
e hombre no creo que lo considere su
sharpest weapon. I understand your
arma más afilada te entiendo tu
argument. Yes, but how much does your father
argumento Sí pero tu papá cuánto
understand about
entiende de
social media? Ah, okay, Yes, of course, I mean, it
redes Ah vale Sí claro o sea también
could also be that he considers that  It's like
puede ser que él considere que es como
a big advertisement, not that I take it very
una gran publicidad no que lo tenga muy
into account. Of course, you say, well, it's
en cuenta Claro que vos decís bueno es
something that I simply don't understand, it's a
algo que simplemente no entiendo es un
success that I don't understand, because seeing it like that, I
éxito que no comprendo pues verlo así yo
don't. Honestly, with what mature criteria are you
no Honestamente Con qué criterio maduro
going to tell someone that they are an
le va a decir a alguien que es un
[ __ ] because because if there is someone who has
gilipolla porque porque si hay alguien
embarrassed themselves for
que ha se ha avergonzado a sí mismo por
more than being a genocide, they are mature, so what are you
más de ser un genoc es maduro entonces
going to say? Oh, you are embarrassing. Oh,
que le va a decir Ay que das vergüenza
at home, how are
ajena Ay por casa cómo
we doing? I don't know if that logic, the little team.
andamos no s si esa lógica el equipito
With all due respect to the little
Con todo el respeto del mundo per el
team, I mean, Michelo, then next to him, the
equipito o sea el michelo luego al lado
minor, the
el mininor
other one, I mean, they don't give any borders,
el otro o sea son no dan cosit borders
eh. Look, Michelo is a
eh Mira de vuelta michelo es un
workhorse, but then he fishes
caballito de batalla pero después pesca
with a net, and that invitation to go to
con red e la invitación esa para ir a
the anti-fascist Venezuelan congresses
los congresos de Venezuela antifascista
and everything else, a lot of
y todo lo demás llegaron un montón de
people came, any stupid
gente cualquier estúpido militante de
left-wing activist would get the
izquierda le llegaba la
invitation, nobody came out, not to say anything, at the
invitación saló nadie no a decir nada de
moment, no. Hey, I had it too.
momento no Oye pues yo también lo tuve
Eh, yes, people have come out to
Eh sí sí han salido
say, they also invited me and I didn't go,
gente decir tambén me invitaron y no fui
several
varios
came out, they passed it on to everyone.  In
saleron se lo pasaron a todos en
Argentina, ideologically speaking, if
Argentina ideológicamente hablando si
you were a Peronist, right-wing or
vos eras peronista de derecha o de
left-wing, or non-Peronist left-wing, you would
izquierda o de izquierda no peronista te
get the invitation, and if you were young, there was a greater
llegaba la invitación y si era joven más
chance of selling the
posibilidades es vender la mentira del
regime's lie. I also wonder about Kim
régimen Yo también me pregunto por Kim
Jong Un, they spend their time trying to sell a
china se gasta en querer vender una
lie to the outside world, but they think it's
mentira para fuera pero creen que es
necessary.
necesario
I don't know why, there are people who
yo que sé para hay hay gente que les
believe them. If you go and watch
cree si vos vas y ves los videos de
Michelo's videos, there are comments from people who
michelo hay comentarios de gente que les
believe them. But outside of what is legal,
cree Pero ya fuera parte de Lo legal
because I understand that, of course, from what you
porque entiendo que claro por lo que me
're telling me, in Argentina you
estás contando en Argentina tú
cannot freely support the dictatorship
libremente no puedes apoyar la dictadura
in Venezuela, no. I mean, a person, well,
de Venezuela no O sea una persona pues
your neighbor could be talking well to you about
tu vecino puede estar hablándote bien de
Maduro, like, long live Maduro.
maduro o sea en plan viva maduro
Really, yes, of course, in Argentina,
realmente sí por supuesto en Argentina
freedom of expression, but legally,
libertad de expresión pero legalmente
but they're going to kick you out, but yes, but here
pero te van a echar pero sí pero acá
someone can go out and record a video
puede salir alguien y grabar un video
supporting the Austrian painter if they want,
apoyando al pintor austríaco si quiere a
what I'm referring to is
lo que me refiero
Michelo can
michelo puede pisar Argentina
easily step foot in Argentina and walk down the street because, of
tranquilamente ir por la calle porque
course, we're talking about the fact that you
claro estamos hablando de que sa cach
have two problems, you have the
tenés dos problemas ten tenés el
problem that, let's see what is
problema de que vamos a ver qué es lo
resolved in what is legal, which I already
que se resuelve en Lo legal que ya te
told you, could end in something or  no and
dije puede terminar en algo o no y
then you have the social problem there's going to be
después tenés el problema social va a
you think you have more than 100,000
haber vos pensa que tenés más de 100,000
Venezuelans who emigrated to
venezolanos que que emigraron a
Argentina
Argentina
So every time you go out on the
Así que todas las veces que salga la
street toss a coin to see if you
calle tir una moneda al aire si te
crossed paths with one or not That's why I tell you he
cruzaba o no con unano Por eso te digo
's in a deserved situation but 100% he
está en una situación merecida pero 100%
bought it all by himself he bought all
se la compró solito él se compró todos
the tickets to be drawn the
los números para para salir sorteada la
pineapple
piña
that you think that only of course I saw your
que tú crees que únicamente claro vi tu
video like no no that has been so
vídeo como no no que ha tenido tanto
successful where you quantify a little what it
éxito donde cuantificas un poco lo que
could have cost Venezuela Michelo
ha podido costarle a Venezuela michelo
but of course what I thought when I
pero claro yo lo que que pensé cuando
saw it was Well of course these could
cuando lo vi fue Bueno claro esto pueden
be expenses or they couldn't be expenses Maybe he does
ser gastos o no pueden ser gastos A lo
n't even pay they don't pay for hotels
mejor incluso no paga no pagan hoteles
but they have an agreement not with the
sino que tienen un acuerdo no con el
regime the hotels Of course but but
régimen los hoteles Claro pero pero
Even if you don't pay for the hotel the maid
Incluso si no pagas el hotel la mucama
still costs you the same the electricity still costs you the
te sigue costando igual la luz te sigue
same the water still costs you the
costando igual el agua te sigue costando
same I mean the expense is there but
igual o sea que el gasto está pero
apart from that I think there must be something else no I
aparte yo creo que habrá algo más no O
mean there will be a salary no V you know that I
sea habrá una un sueldo no V sabes que
think no we will never know no You
yo creo que no nunca lo sabremos no Tú
think that no  No, I think there should be
crees que no no yo creo que debe haber
travel expenses, you see this, but you
viáticos on gast esto viste pero vos
know that I think it's so sad that
sabes que yo creo que es tan triste que
no, then you say, then without
no que entonces ya dices tú entonces sin
that and per veil it in this way,
eso y per velo de esta manera
look in Argentina, organically, there are
mira en Argentina orgánicamente hay
people who cry and go out of their way for
gente que llora y se desvive por
Cristina Fernndez. It doesn't matter how much of a
Cristina Fernández No importa qu tan
thief she is, in Bolivia, there are people who go
ladrona sea en Bolivia hay gente que se
out of their way and cry organically for them. It doesn't
desvive y llora orgánicamente porales No
matter how much of a pedophile he is. But well,
importa que tan pedófilo sea Pero bueno
excuse the word, but it is
perdón por la palabra pero es
that, and every leader, no matter how much of a son of a
eso y cada cada líder por más hijo de
[ __ ] he is, has people who cry
[__] que sea tiene tiene gente que llora
and live it. So, Michelo, at this
y la vive Entonces michelo en este
moment, is in a country where, it is
momento está en un país donde si es
true that there are people who are going to love him
cierto que hay gente que lo va a querer
because there are people who want to beat him to
porque haber gente que lo quiere matar a
death in Venezuela itself, but they are not
palos en el mismo Venezuela pero que no
going to do it because they already know what
lo va a hacer porque ya saben lo que
happens if you get close. So he is in a
pasa si te acercas Entonces está en un
country where the one who hates him is not going to
país donde el que lo odia no le va a
touch a hair on his head and the one who loves him is going to
tocar un pelo y el que lo ama Se lo va a
take him out to hug him and there will be a lot of
sacar a abrazar y haber un montón de
people who genuinely love him, yes, there will be
gente que lo ame genuinamente si haber
a lot of people who love Maduro.
un montón de gente que ame a maduro
So, he is living a reality
Entonces él está viviendo una realidad
that perhaps surpasses the reality that  I would have
que quizás supera la realidad que le
waited in Argentina H not only
hubiese esperado en Argentina H ya no lo
economically but he was lacking a
económico sino que estaba a falto de un
little case, I mean, seeing himself in
casito o sea eso del verse en el
Congress giving a rally and people
congreso dando un miting que la gente se
getting excited about everything, everything, all
venga arriba en todo en todo en todo
this. This is a micro erection to the ego
esto Esto es una micro erección al ego
in everything, yes, it is important, it is true, it is
en todo s á es importante verd es
absurd, it is absurd because the one who you
absurdo es absurdo porque el que tú
know that if you do well on YouTube, [ __ ]
sabes que si te va bien en YouTube [__]
and creating content and having a
y creando contenido y teniendo una
community, damn, what do you gain on YouTube,
comunidad [__] Qué ganas en YouTube no
his videos don't work on YouTube,
funciona su videoos en YouTube no lo
nobody does it clearly. Well, but you Remember
nadie clar Bueno pero vos Acuérdate de
not to think of reality as
no pienses la realidad como que como vos
yourself being the scale. I mean, don't weigh reality
mismo siendo la balanza O sea no peses
taking yourself as the scale. You
la realidad tomándote como balanza vos
are successful, maybe he thinks he can't
sos exitoso quizás él cree que no lo
be, so he chose another path, he took the
puede ser entonces eligió otro camino se
wrong path. Why do you think that of
equivocó de camino por qué crees que de
all the people who are giving him a hard time, he
toda la gente que le está dando caña te
has answered you because you are one of the
ha contestado a ti porque eres de los
few that he doesn't answer. In
pocos a los que no le contesta en
general, he answers everyone. Historically, he
general le contesta todos históricamente
answered everyone. Yes, but I think my bullet
les contestaba a todos Sí pero mi bala
was the one that went in the most, eh. Because
creo que fue la que más entró eh Porque
the argument is simple, it's Chee, you were
el argumento es sencillo es Che estabas
in a poor country stopping a hot c
en un país pobre parando un hot c
stars  how did you pay for it there is no there is no there is no
estrellas cómo lo pagaste no hay no hay
more nothing that is not a
no hay más nada que eso no es una
political criticism it is not a criticism nothing
crítica política no es una crítica nada
is Che Why are you rich in a
es Che Por qué sos rico en un país de
poor country it is that simple then eh because of
pobre es así de sencillo entonces eh por
its simplicity the bullet enters and he has tried to make me
su simpleza entra la bala y ha intentado
laugh I don't know he tries I don't know what he
a mí me dan risa no sé intenta no sé qué
wants to do more than I saw that he
quiere hacer yo más que vi que te
answered you and Dallas Well to
contestó a ti y al Dallas Bueno al
Dallas he started to say it was s he started
Dallas empezó a decirle era s al empezó
with that Well to me there is nothing to
con esa Bueno a mí no hay nada que
tell me that is also the other story
decirme esa también es la otra historia
I no no I do not have controversies hab have you
yo no no no tengo polémicas hab no has
thought of challenging him to a debate why the [ __ ] dude
pensado retarle un debate para qué [__]
No I I understand you but but
tipito No yo yo te entiendo pero pero
What is the end is he going to talk to me about
Cuál es el fin me va a hablar de
Palestine 7
Palestina 7
seconds I would be the bomb eh I mean it would be
segundos Yo sería la bomba eh o sea
Yes it would be cinema it would be cinema As
sería Sí sería cine sería cine Como
content
contenido
but yes but to me I am not going to
pero sí pero a mí a mí no me a
see more than making him step on the stick and
ver más que hacerlo pisar el palito y
bring him his own problems I don't think he is
traerle propio problemas no creo que sea
that stupid I am sincere Because if I
tan estúpido Te soy sincero Porque si yo
were a debate with him my strategy
fuera un debate con él mi estrategia
would be to make him step on sticks that they
sería hacerle pisar palitos que que lo
will leave him I mean no that I win the
van quedar o sea no que yo gane el
debate I would care very little if there are
debate me importaría muy poco que queden
clips in which  He admits things without realizing it
clips en los cual él admita cosas sin
and then causes
darse cuenta y después le traiga
problems with his own regime, that is,
problemas con su propio régimen o sea
making him put his life at risk
hacerlo hacer que su vida corra riesgo
at the hands of Maduro himself because because
en mano del propio maduro porque porque
nothing matters, you see, I would go for that and he
no importa nada viste yo iría por eso y
is not that stupid, he is not that stupid
no es tan estúpido no es tan boludo
because it would be, it would genuinely be
porque es sería sería genuinamente un
suicide. Honestly, it's crazy, right?
suicidio Honestamente es una locura ent
No, no, I don't think he's that stupid. I do
no no no creo que sea tan
n't think so. We could invite him if he wants him to
taría No creo igual lo invitamos si
come, that would be great, eh, I
queré que venga hosa sería la bomba eh o
mean, I know.
sea se yo